The Mainprice Deposit
The Mainprice Deposit
- Documents relating to the Gorton and Culceth families, 1640-1813; GB/418/E.8.15; GB/418/Main/4; 33 files; Chetham's Library
  - Lease of a dye-house etc in Salford, 28 Jan 1725; GB/418/E.8.15 (21); GB/418/Main/4/21; Chetham's Library
    From Robert Booth of Salford et al to John Kay of Salford
  - Conveyance of land in Manchester, 12 May 1727; GB/418/E.8.15 (22); GB/418/Main/4/22; Chetham's Library
    From John Colsworthy of Exon et al to Joseph Vigor of Manchester
  - Will of Theophilus Badeley of Chorlton Row, 2 Aug 1728; GB/418/E.8.15 (23); GB/418/Main/4/23; Chetham's Library
  - Appointment of new trustees for charity left by John Marsh of Elston for poor of Bolton and Little Hulton, 25 Sep 1733; GB/418/E.8.15 (24); GB/418/Main/4/24; Chetham's Library
  - Will of Edward Leech of Salford, 18 Feb 1754; GB/418/E.8.15 (25); GB/418/Main/4/25; Chetham's Library
  - Conveyance of land in Manchester, 26 Jun 1756; GB/418/E.8.15 (26); GB/418/Main/4/26; Chetham's Library
    From Thomas Smith of Manchester, alehouse keeper et al to Dauntsey Smith of Manchester
  - Will of Edward Leach of Salford, 6 Aug 1759; GB/418/E.8.15 (27); GB/418/Main/4/27; Chetham's Library
  - Conveyance of land in Eccles, 18 Sep 1759; GB/418/E.8.15 (28); GB/418/Main/4/28; Chetham's Library
    From Lady Penelope Cholmondely to Richard Worsley and Thomas Chorlton
  - Assignment of a lease of land in Manchester, 1760; GB/418/E.8.15 (29); GB/418/Main/4/29; Chetham's Library
    From Edward Radcliffe of Manchester and Thomas Bancroft of Manchester to William Bancroft of Manchester
  - Probate of will of Ralph Sandiford of Manchester, 18 Jul 1763; GB/418/E.8.15 (30); GB/418/Main/4/30; Chetham's Library
  - Probate of will of Dauntesey Smith of Manchester, attorney, 12 Aug 1771; GB/418/E.8.15 (31); GB/418/Main/4/31; Chetham's Library
  - Probate of will of Thomas Barker DD princial of Brazen Nose College, Oxford, 29 Jul 1785; GB/418/E.8.15 (32); GB/418/Main/4/32; Chetham's Library
  - Agreement by its lessees concerning New Cloth Hall in Salford, erected by John Clegg, 14 Dec 1813; GB/418/E.8.15 (33); GB/418/Main/4/33; Chetham's Library
- Documents relating to Lancashire and Cheshire, 1564-1809; GB/418/F.1.1-20 & F.2.1-12; GB/418/Main/5; 632 files; Chetham's Library
  This collection of documents was formerly housed in trunks and boxes in the Cabinet Room in Chetham's Library. The library has no records relating to this material, although it was clearly deposited by Taylor, Kirkman and Mainprice, solicitors to the Hospital and Library.
  The material, which was arranged in no order whatsoever, was separated into two collections: F1.1-F.1.20, 20 boxes chiefly relating to Lancashire and Cheshire, and F.2.1-F.2.2, 12 boxes containing 249 documents relating to other counties.
  Material of local interest was listed by Ian McAlpine, Library volunteer, in 1990-91. On grounds of convenience, however, the documents were then physically sorted into chronological order within an alphabetical order of places. Documents which were gathered into bundles have not been interfered with, hence material on Hindley is found with Abram and Hindley and material relating to the Culceth family of Culceth has been kept in the order in which it was found. Documents relating to places unspecified are listed at the end of the handlist.
  The documents have been numbered by the first letter of the place and then in chronological order. Collections relating to Manchester and Salford are numbered respectively Ma, Sa, whilst unspecified documents are numbered X1-14. All of the documents have been labelled in a form that corresponds to the handlist.
  - Documents relating to Abram and Hindley, 1671-1846; GB/418/F.1.1 (A1-33); GB/418/Main/5/1; 26 files; Chetham's Library
    - Lease and release of land in Abram, 25 & 26 May 1671; GB/418/F.1.1 (A1 & A2); GB/418/Main/5/1/1; 2 items; Chetham's Library
      From James Duckenfield of Aspull to Thurstan Pemberton of West Haughton.
      Lease torn.
    - Bond in £300 to perform covenants, 26 May 1671; GB/418/F.1.1 (A3); GB/418/Main/5/1/2; Chetham's Library
      From James Duckenfield of Aspull of Thurstan Pemberton of Westhoughton
    - Lease and release of land in Abram, 27 & 28 Feb 1676; GB/418/F.1.1 (A4 & A5); GB/418/Main/5/1/3; 2 items; Chetham's Library
      From Thurstan Pemberton of Westleigh, Cowper to George Mather of Abram
    - Bond in £300 to perform covenants, 28 Feb 1676; GB/418/F.1.1 (A6); GB/418/Main/5/1/4; Chetham's Library
      From Thurstan Pemberton of Westleigh Cowper to George Mather of Abram
    - Office copy of will of James Naylor of Abram, yeo, 11 Sep 1773; GB/418/F.1.1 (A7); GB/418/Main/5/1/5; Chetham's Library
    - Conveyance of land in Abram, 18 Sep 1773; GB/418/F.1.1 (A8); GB/418/Main/5/1/6; Chetham's Library
      From James Naylor of Abram to John Anderton of Abram, yeo
    - Deed to declare uses of a fine concerning land in Abram and Chowbent, 16 Dec 1774; GB/418/F.1.1 (A9); GB/418/Main/5/1/7; Chetham's Library
      From John Pennington of Wigan plaintiff, John Anderton and Martha Higginson of Wigan, deforciants
    - Lease and release of land in Hindley, 12 & 13 Feb 1781; GB/418/F.1.1 (A10 & A11); GB/418/Main/5/1/8; 2 items; Chetham's Library
      From John Walmesley et al, devisees of will of Ann Walmesley to John and Ann Parr of Preston and members of Walmesley family
    - Bargain and sale of land in Hindley, 17 May 1785; GB/418/F.1.1 (A12); GB/418/Main/5/1/9; Chetham's Library
      From John Sanderson of Bickershaw to John Green of Everton
    - Assignment of land in Hindley, 24 Feb 1787; GB/418/F.1.1 (A13); GB/418/Main/5/1/10; Chetham's Library
      From William Clayton of Wigan to James Taylor of Leigh
    - Conveyance of land in Abram, 1 Apr 1758; GB/418/F.1.1 (A14); GB/418/Main/5/1/11; Chetham's Library
      From Nicholas Mather of Clayton in the Woods to James Naylor of Abram
    - Bond in £800 of indemnity against his wife's dower from Nicholas Mather of Clayton in the Woods to James Naylor of Abram, 1 Apr 1758; GB/418/F.1.1 (A15); GB/418/Main/5/1/12; Chetham's Library
    - Probate copy of will of John Naylor of Abram, 14 Nov 1764; GB/418/F.1.1 (A16); GB/418/Main/5/1/13; Chetham's Library
    - Demise of land in Abram, 13 Apr 1776; GB/418/F.1.1 (A17); GB/418/Main/5/1/14; Chetham's Library
      From Richard Anderton of Hindley, chapman, to James Beard of New Mill in Glossop
    - Lease and release of land in Hindley, 3 & 4 Feb 1781; GB/418/F.1.1 (A19 & A20); GB/418/Main/5/1/15; 2 items; Chetham's Library
      From Richard Anderton of Hindley to John Sanderson of Bickershaw
    - Assignment of land in Abram, 3 Feb 1781; GB/418/F.1.1 (A21); GB/418/Main/5/1/16; Chetham's Library
      From Mary Beard of New Mill in Glossop et al to James Taylor of Leigh
    - Mortgage of land in Abram, 23 Feb 1781; GB/418/F.1.1 (A22); GB/418/Main/5/1/17; Chetham's Library
      From John Sanderson of Bickershaw to Elizabeth Fazackerley of Bickershaw
    - Final concord at Lancaster concerning land in Abram and Hindley, 20 Mar 1780; GB/418/F.1.1 (A23); GB/418/Main/5/1/18; Chetham's Library
      Between John Sanderson, yeo, plaintiff, Richard Anderton and May his wife deforciants
    - Conveyance of land in Abram, 17 May 1785; GB/418/F.1.1 (A24); GB/418/Main/5/1/19; Chetham's Library
      From John Sanderson of Bickershaw and Elizabeth Fazackerley of Bickershaw to John Green of Everton
    - Assignment of land in Hindley and Abram, 24 Feb 1787; GB/418/F.1.1 (A25); GB/418/Main/5/1/20; Chetham's Library
      From James Taylor of Leigh to Robert Smith of Tyldesley with Shackerley
    - Lease and release of land in Hindley, 23 & 24 Feb 1787; GB/418/F.1.1 (A26 & A27); GB/418/Main/5/1/21; 2 items; Chetham's Library
      From John Green of Everton, gent, John Sanderson of Culcheth, yeo, and Henry Sanderson of Culcheth, yeo, to Peter Arrowsmith of Astley, chapman
    - Probate copy of will of Robert Smith of Tildesley (Tyldesley) with Shackerley, corn dealer, 30 Jun 1797; GB/418/F.1.1 (A28); GB/418/Main/5/1/22; Chetham's Library
    - Lease and release of land in Abram, 5 & 6 Dec 1811; GB/418/F.1.1 (A29 & A30); GB/418/Main/5/1/23; 2 items; Chetham's Library
      From Peter Arrowsmith of Astley, gent to Elias Chadwick of Swinton, cotton merchant and Strettell Chadwick of Wigan, gent
    - Assignment of land in Abram and Hindley in trust for Elias Chadwick of Swinton, 6 Dec 1811; GB/418/F.1.1 (A31); GB/418/Main/5/1/24; Chetham's Library
      From John Smith to Roger Grimshaw
    - Assignment of residue of lease of land in Hindley in trust for Elias Chadwick of Swinton, 6 Dec 1811; GB/418/F.1.1 (A32); GB/418/Main/5/1/25; Chetham's Library
      From William Clayton of Wigan to Robert Seddon
    - Conveyance of land in Abram, 16 Jan 1846; GB/418/F.1.1 (A33); GB/418/Main/5/1/26; Chetham's Library
      From Henry Strettell Chadwick of Swinton to Abraham Ackers of Abram
  - Document relating to Adlington, 1789; GB/418/F.1.2 (A34); GB/418/Main/5/2; 1 file; Chetham's Library
    - Marriage settlement between Hannah Aspinall of Adlington, Lancs and Rev Griffith Williams of Bishopsgate, London, 22 Dec 1789; GB/418/F.1.2 (A34); GB/418/Main/5/2/1; Chetham's Library
  - Documents relating to Allerton, 1812; GB/418/F.1.2 (A35 & A36); GB/418/Main/5/3; 2 items; Chetham's Library
    - Lease and release of land in Allerton, 20 & 21 Oct 1812; GB/418/F.1.2 (A35 & A36); GB/418/Main/5/3/1; 1 file; Chetham's Library
      From devisees of James Clegg to Jonathon Hobson of Liverpool, merchant and Joshua Lace of Liverpool, gent
  - Document relating to Altrincham, 1764; GB/418/F.1.2 (A37); GB/418/Main/5/4; 1 file; Chetham's Library
    - Conveyance of land in Altrincham co Ches, 17 Oct 1764; GB/418/F.1.2 (A37); GB/418/Main/5/4/1; Chetham's Library
      From John Royd and William Turner of Warrington to Michael Bentley of Newton
  - Documents relating to Ardwick, 1756-1834; GB/418/F.1.2 (A38-A40); GB/418/Main/5/5; 3 files; Chetham's Library
    - Assignment by John Worrall Jr of Ardwick to John Worrall Sr of Adlington et al of his effects, 11 Dec 1756; GB/418/F.1.2 (A38); GB/418/Main/5/5/1; Chetham's Library
    - Articles of partnership between members of Lees family of Ardwick and Gorton, merchants, 7 Jun 1827; GB/418/F.1.2 (A39); GB/418/Main/5/5/2; Chetham's Library
    - Articles of partnership between Aaron Lees of Ardwick and William Harrison Lees of Gorton, cotton-spinner, 1 Dec 1834; GB/418/F.1.2 (A40); GB/418/Main/5/5/3; Chetham's Library
  - Document relating to Ashton-Under-Lyne, 1762; GB/418/F.1.2 (A41); GB/418/Main/5/6; 1 file; Chetham's Library
    - Conveyance of a legacy, 30 Jul 1762; GB/418/F.1.2 (A41); GB/418/Main/5/6/1; Chetham's Library
      From Anthony Ward of Ashton-under-Lyne and Mary his wife to John Seplith of Saddleworth and Josiah Boardman of Manchester
  - Documents relating to Aspull, 1761-1768; GB/418/F.1.2 (A42-A46); GB/418/Main/5/7; 5 files; Chetham's Library
    - Conveyance of land in Aspull, 30 May 1761; GB/418/F.1.2 (A42); GB/418/Main/5/7/1; Chetham's Library
      From James Worthington, yeo of Aspull and Elizabeth his wife to Charles Houghton of Wigan, chapman and Elizabeth his wife
    - Assignment of land in Aspull, 1 May 1762; GB/418/F.1.2 (A43); GB/418/Main/5/7/2; Chetham's Library
      From Charles Houghton of Aspull, chapman to Thomas Haughton of Rainford
    - Mortgage of land in Aspull, 30 Oct 1766; GB/418/F.1.2 (A44); GB/418/Main/5/7/3; Chetham's Library
      From Thomas Boughton of Rainford, clay potter et al to John Stopforth of Dalton
    - Assignment of part of estate in Aspull, 6 Jan 1768; GB/418/F.1.2 (A45); GB/418/Main/5/7/4; Chetham's Library
      From John Stopforth of Dalton et al to Elias Chadwick of Wigan
    - Assignment of land in Aspull, 9 Jan 1768; GB/418/F.1.2 (A46); GB/418/Main/5/7/5; Chetham's Library
      From Charles Houghton of Aspull to Elias Chadwick of Wigan
  - Document relating to Astley, 1799; GB/418/F.1.2 (A47); GB/418/Main/5/8; 1 file; Chetham's Library
    - Final concord at Lancaster of land in Astley, 23 Aug 1799; GB/418/F.1.2 (A47); GB/418/Main/5/8/1; Chetham's Library
      Between Arnold Farnworth, plaintiff and William Grundy, Sarah his wife, John Marsh, Margaret his wife, Phineas Smith and Catherine his wife, deforciants
  - Documents relating to Atherton, 1794; GB/418/F.1.2 (A48 & A49); GB/418/Main/5/9; 2 files; Chetham's Library
    - Conveyance of land in Atherton, 5 Feb 1794; GB/418/F.1.2 (A48); GB/418/Main/5/9/1; Chetham's Library
      Between Thomas Withington of Atherton to Messrs Hodson et al
    - Conveyance of land in Atherton, 6 Feb 1794; GB/418/F.1.2 (A49); GB/418/Main/5/9/2; Chetham's Library
  - Document relating to Balderstone, 1740; GB/418/F.1.3 (B1); GB/418/Main/5/10; 1 file; Chetham's Library
    - Conveyance of land in Balderstone and Castleton, 1740; GB/418/F.1.3 (B1); GB/418/Main/5/10/1; Chetham's Library
      From Thomas Whitehead of Saddleworth, stapler to Ralph Whitehead
  - Documents relating to Barton-Upon-Irwell, 1719-1909; GB/418/F.1.3 (B2-B10); GB/418/Main/5/11; 8 files; Chetham's Library
    - Conveyance of land in Barton-upon-Irwell, 30 May 1719; GB/418/F.1.3 (B2); GB/418/Main/5/11/1; Chetham's Library
      From Thomas Gooden of Barton-upon-Irwell to Robert Cooke
    - Agreement between John and Thomas Gooden of Barton-upon-Irwell and their creditors, 12 Mar 1722; GB/418/F.1.3 (B3); GB/418/Main/5/11/2; Chetham's Library
    - Conveyance of land in Barton-upon-Irwell, 21 Mar 1778; GB/418/F.1.3 (B4); GB/418/Main/5/11/3; Chetham's Library
      From Thomas Waring of Park Hall, yeo, et al to James Cooke of Salford, gent
    - Bond in £1296 concerning peaceable enjoyment of land in Barton-upon-Irwell, 21 Mar 1778; GB/418/F.1.3 (B5); GB/418/Main/5/11/4; Chetham's Library
      From Thomas Waring of Park Hall, yeo, and William Waring of Wigan, butcher, to James Cooke
    - Conveyance of land in Barton-upon-Irwell, 18 Sep 1778; GB/418/F.1.3 (B6); GB/418/Main/5/11/5; Chetham's Library
      From Humphrey Trafford of Trafford, esq, to James Cooke of Salford, gent
    - Final agreement at Court in Lancaster concerning land in Barton-upon-Irwell, 29 Aug 1807; GB/418/F.1.3 (B7); GB/418/Main/5/11/6; Chetham's Library
      Between Charles Cooke of Raincliff and Richard Roberts, Ann his wife and James Taylor and Mary his wife
    - Assignment of sale of land in Barton-upon-Irwell, 6 Nov 1810; GB/418/F.1.3 (B8 & B9); GB/418/Main/5/11/7; 2 items; Chetham's Library
      From Thomas Aldred of Salford and John Farnworth Strettell of Pendleton to William Lomax
    - Envelope containing correspondence concerning donations in memory of Rev A.E. Francis, vicar of Barton-upon-Irwell who died 23 Jul 1898, 1898-1909; GB/418/F.1.3 (B10); GB/418/Main/5/11/8; Chetham's Library
  - Documents relating to Blackley, 1678-1804; GB/418/F.1.3 (B11-B24); GB/418/Main/5/12; 13 files; Chetham's Library
    - Will of John Travis of Blackley, yeo, 6 Jul 1678; GB/418/F.1.3 (B11); GB/418/Main/5/12/1; Chetham's Library
    - Will of Robert Litchford of Blackley, gent, 26 Dec 1710; GB/418/F.1.3 (B12); GB/418/Main/5/12/2; Chetham's Library
    - Conveyance [of land in Blackley], 21 Nov 1719; GB/418/F.1.3 (B13); GB/418/Main/5/12/3; Chetham's Library
      From John Buerdsell of Blackley, yeo and Thomas Jackson of Blackley, chapman to Litchford Flitcroft of Manchester gent, and Samuel Ogden of Blackley
    - Conveyance of land in Blackley for a school, 13 Oct 1725; GB/418/F.1.3 (B14); GB/418/Main/5/12/4; Chetham's Library
      From John Buerdsall of Blackley, yeo and Samuel Ogden of Blackley, yeo to Francis Broome of Blackley, labourer, William Fenton of Blackley, yeo et al
    - Appointment of four new trustees of will of Thomas Travis of Blackley, 25 Jan 1744; GB/418/F.1.3 (B15); GB/418/Main/5/12/5; Chetham's Library
    - Appointment of new trustees of Blackley school, 5 Feb 1755; GB/418/F.1.3 (B16); GB/418/Main/5/12/6; Chetham's Library
    - Appointment of four new trustees of will of Thomas Travis of Blackley, 25 Oct 1762; GB/418/F.1.3 (B17); GB/418/Main/5/12/7; Chetham's Library
    - Decision of Attorney General concerning complaint made by Jacob Radcliffe against trustees of Blackley school, 11 April 1764; GB/418/F.1.3 (B18); GB/418/Main/5/12/8; Chetham's Library
    - Appointment of new trustees of Blackley school, 30 Oct 1772; GB/418/F.1.3 (B19); GB/418/Main/5/12/9; Chetham's Library
    - Grant of annuity of £5 a year to master of Blackley school, 3 Dec 1781; GB/418/F.1.3 (B20); GB/418/Main/5/12/10; Chetham's Library
    - Final concord at Lancaster of land in Blakeley (Blackley) and Gorton, 24 Mar 1788; GB/418/F.1.3 (B21); GB/418/Main/5/12/11; Chetham's Library
      Between Nicholas Grimshaw, plaintiff and Edward Hulton, Martha his wife, Thomas Bradock and Alice his wife, deforceants
    - John and Edward Hulton's appointment of new trustees of will of Thomas Travis of Blackley, 24 Dec 1795; GB/418/F.1.3 (B22); GB/418/Main/5/12/12; Chetham's Library
    - Lease and release of land in Blackley and pew in Manchester Collegiate Church, 3 & 4 Dec 1804; GB/418/F.1.3 (B23 & B24); GB/418/Main/5/12/13; Chetham's Library
      From Samuel Taylor of Moston, merchant et al to William Cross of Preston
  - Documents relating to Bolton, 1733-1785; GB/418/F.1.3 (B25-B27); GB/418/Main/5/13; 3 files; Chetham's Library
    - Conveyance of land in Bolton, 25 Sep 1733; GB/418/F.1.3 (B25); GB/418/Main/5/13/1; Chetham's Library
      From James Marsh of Westhoughton and Richard Farnworth of Farnworth to John Parker of Breightmet, George Kenyon of Peel et al
    - Conveyance of land in Bolton, 9 Aug 1767; GB/418/F.1.3 (B26); GB/418/Main/5/13/2; Chetham's Library
      From John Parker of Booth, George Kenyon of Little Hulton and Robert Bullough of Breighmett to John Parker of Millhouses, co Ches, for Thomas Shawe of Bolton, George Kenyon of Wigan and Rev Robert Kenyon of Salford
    - Grant of trusteeships of Marsh's Charity, Bolton, 1 Oct 1785; GB/418/F.1.3 (B27); GB/418/Main/5/13/3; Chetham's Library
      For Rev John Parker of Asle et al to Thomas Packet et al
  - Documents relating to Bury, 1760-1866; GB/418/F.1.3 (B28-B35); GB/418/Main/5/14; 5 files; Chetham's Library
    - Conveyance of a pew in Bury church, 18 Aug 1760; GB/418/F.1.3 (B28); GB/418/Main/5/14/1; Chetham's Library
      From Joseph Wolstenholme of Bury to Uriah Cooper of Eccles and Thomas Hutchinson of Bury
    - Lease of land in Bury, 10 Aug 1812; GB/418/F.1.3 (B29, B30, B31); GB/418/Main/5/14/2; 3 items; Chetham's Library
      From Edward, Earl of Derby, to Jonathan Beever of Bury
    - Lease of land in Bury, 31 Aug 1814; GB/418/F.1.3 (B32); GB/418/Main/5/14/3; Chetham's Library
      From Edward, Earl of Derby to Jonathon Beever of Bury
    - Counterpart lease of Hampson Mills near Bury, 12 Oct 1825; GB/418/F.1.3 (B33); GB/418/Main/5/14/4; Chetham's Library
      From Jonathan Beever of Cefn Coch, Denbighshire and John Holt Beever of Manchester to John Nuttall of Unsworth
    - Lease and release of land in Bury, 21 & 22 Feb 1866; GB/418/F.1.3 (B34 & B35); GB/418/Main/5/14/5; 2 items; Chetham's Library
      From Jonathon Beever of Bury, merchant, to John Holt Beever of Salford, merchant
  - Document relating to Butterworth, 1730; GB/418/F.1.3 (B36); GB/418/Main/5/15; 1 file; Chetham's Library
    - Conveyance of land in Butterworth, 29 Jan 1730; GB/418/F.1.3 (B36); GB/418/Main/5/15/1; Chetham's Library
      From Mary Dawson of Rochdale to John Haigh of Milnrow and Robert Butterworth of Butterworth
  - Documents relating to Castleton, 1694 & 1749; GB/418/F.1.4 (C1 & C2); GB/418/Main/5/16; 2 files; Chetham's Library
    - Bond in £300 to perform covenants, 14 Apr 1694; GB/418/F.1.4 (C1); GB/418/Main/5/16/1; Chetham's Library
      From John Atkinson of Castleton, Lancs to Jane Atkinson of Brumedge
    - Deed poll of Sarah, wife of Nicholas Shuttleworth of Castleton, gent, 14 Jul 1749; GB/418/F.1.4 (C2); GB/418/Main/5/16/2; Chetham's Library
  - Documents relating to Cheetwood, 1816; GB/418/F.1.4 (C3 & C4); GB/418/Main/5/17; 1 file; Chetham's Library
    - Lease and release of land in Cheetwood, 29 Oct 1816; GB/418/F.1.4 (C3 & C4); GB/418/Main/5/17/1; 2 items; Chetham's Library
      From Sir Oswald Mosley of Rolleston, Staffs to John Jackson of Manchester, manufacturer
  - Documents relating to Chetham, 1710; GB/418/F.1.4 (C5); GB/418/Main/5/18; 1 file; Chetham's Library
    - Final concord at Lancaster concerning land in Chetham, 6 Apr 1710; GB/418/F.1.4 (C5); GB/418/Main/5/18/1; Chetham's Library
      Between James [?] and Richard [?Kay], plaintiffs, James Holte and [?], deforciants.
      Some names unidentifiable.
  - Documents relating to Chorlton, 1704-1831; GB/418/F.1.4 (C6-C19); GB/418/Main/5/19; 14 files; Chetham's Library
    - Agreement concerning land in Chorlton, 1 Jun 1704; GB/418/F.1.4 (C6); GB/418/Main/5/19/1; Chetham's Library
      Between John Cock, father and son of Gorton and Robert Jepson of Chorlton
    - Lease of land in Chorlton, 8 Jun 1704; GB/418/F.1.4 (C7); GB/418/Main/5/19/2; Chetham's Library
      From John Cock, father and son of Gorton to Robert Jepson of Chorlton
    - Release of land in Chorlton, 29 Jun 1704; GB/418/F.1.4 (C8); GB/418/Main/5/19/3; Chetham's Library
    - Copy will of Robert Jepson of Chorlton, 20 Jul 1709; GB/418/F.1.4 (C9); GB/418/Main/5/19/4; Chetham's Library
    - Conditional surrender of land in Chorlton, 4 Mar 1713; GB/418/F.1.4 (C10); GB/418/Main/5/19/5; Chetham's Library
      From Richard Richarson of Misterton, co Notts, to his son Benjamin
    - Covenant from Richard Richardson of Misterton, co Notts, concerning fine and recovery of land in Chorlton, 6 Mar 1713; GB/418/F.1.4 (C11); GB/418/Main/5/19/6; Chetham's Library
    - Final concord at Lancaster concerning land in Chorlton, 28 Mar 1713; GB/418/F.1.4 (C12); GB/418/Main/5/19/7; Chetham's Library
      Between Hugh Parr and John Waite, plaintiffs and Benjamin Richardson, deforciant
    - Recovery at Lancaster concerning land at Chorlton, 28 Mar 1713; GB/418/F.1.4 (C13); GB/418/Main/5/19/8; Chetham's Library
      Between Hugh Parr and John Waite, plaintiffs, Benjamin Richardson, deforciant
    - Recovery at Lancaster (details uncertain), 26 Mar 1720; GB/418/F.1.4 (C14); GB/418/Main/5/19/9; Chetham's Library
    - Agreement concerning lease of land in Chorlton, 17 Jan 1765; GB/418/F.1.4 (C15); GB/418/Main/5/19/10; Chetham's Library
      Between John Johnson of Stretford, his family and Richard Pearson of Chorlton
    - Letter from John Clough concerning will of Hannah Hall of Chorlton Row (Roe), 31 Jan 1803; GB/418/F.1.4 (C16); GB/418/Main/5/19/11; Chetham's Library
    - Receipt for £55 from Matthew Royle to James Holland, 31 Jan 1803; GB/418/F.1.4 (C17); GB/418/Main/5/19/12; Chetham's Library
    - Will of John Wood of Chorlton Row (Roe), gent, 23 Jan 1821; GB/418/F.1.4 (C18); GB/418/Main/5/19/13; Chetham's Library
    - Release of land in Chorlton Row (Roe), 12 Jul 1831; GB/418/F.1.4 (C19); GB/418/Main/5/19/14; Chetham's Library
      From John and Mary Ann Barnes of Manchester, clerk to George Dawson of Whitefield, cotton manufacturer and James Hibbert Wanklyn of Manchester, merchant
  - Document relating to Chowbent, 1764; GB/418/F.1.4 (C20); GB/418/Main/5/20; 1 file; Chetham's Library
    - Conveyance of the estate of Henry Morris, bankrupt, 25 Feb 1764; GB/418/F.1.4 (C20); GB/418/Main/5/20/1; Chetham's Library
      From George Kenyon of Peel, Allen Vigor of Manchester and Joseph Chippindale to John Mort of Chowbent, John Worthington of Chowbent and John Marsh of Chowbent.
  - Document relating to Clifton, 1665; GB/418/F.1.4 (C21); GB/418/Main/5/21; 1 file; Chetham's Library
    - Bond in £40 to perform covenants, 3 May 1665; GB/418/F.1.4 (C21); GB/418/Main/5/21/1; Chetham's Library